"hello Mrs Cat, what flavor would you
like? Is the vanilla ice cream nice,
oh I don't know I haven't tried it yet"
If like me you've got a young kid who is
obsessed with ice pops or popsicles
if they're called where you're from,
you know the importance of a good recipe that's
low in sugar. That's what we're going to do today,
we're going to start our popsicle playlist with
Peppa Pig Ultra low sugar strawberry popsicle
It was always expected that my kid grew up wanting
ice cream, she's 3 and 1/2 years old now she loves
ice pops, popsicles, whatever you want to call
them. I bought some molds from TEMU and Amazon
and various other places but most recipes online
for kids ice pops are just milk sugar and some
kind of artificial color and flavor which.....
yeah I'm not a big fan of so what I thought I'd
do is I'd open up the popsicle series by doing
a healthy strawberry ice pop for kids for adults
as well cuz they taste delicious and in this I
use alos so whilst it is not no sugar because
I also use corn syrup it's really low sugar so
let's just get on and make them so in our pan
we're going to add 65g of nice fresh strawberries
chopped up into relatively small... I think I've
just quarted these ones... and into that we're
just going to put 1/4 of a cup of water and
that's to make sure that these strawberries don't
burn whilst we heat them as they start coming up
to temperature this is on a medium high heat you
can see that the sugars in the strawberries will
start to break down the strawberries are merting
themselves and they become a really soft fruit
that we can actually start breaking up with our
silicon utensil now it's time to turn the heat off
because we're going to add in our corn syrup this
is only 6g, add in some of our milk and our cream
mixture not a lot of cream in here but we're going
to start stirring it together cuz we want to make
sure that that strawberry flavor is completely
homogenized in our Dairy once you're happy with
it add in the rest of your milk and your cream
mixture and start giving it a nice stir make
sure it's all coming together nicely cuz the final
stage of this is adding in our milk powder and our
alos so add that in and stir it really well
everything will dissolve really easily because
your Dairy your liquid is nice and warm after a
minute or two of stirring we can actually just
take it off this residual heat cuz we're going to
pour it into our molds so off heat if you've got
any larger lumps that you want to break up you can
use a blender you can use a potato masher you can
use anything you've got to hand just to break up
those large pieces of strawberry make sure that
they're all nice and small and easy to go into our
molds then just slowly pour them in making sure to
fill your molds right the way to the top I've made
just enough mixture here for these seven molds the
ones we're doing first here they're 30g total
weight per ice pop the ones below are 50g I'm
going to give you all of the nutritional values of
these in a minute nice and healthy for the little
kidos so with all of the molds completely filled
up put the lids on covers if they have them if not
put a bit of shrink wrap over the top
and put them in your freezer to harden
off pepper pig strawberry popsicles there's
a few different shapes but this mold came
off of Amazon I think um 30 G this Popsicle
is and nutritional values are as follows so
this is po 100 G so basically 1/3 yeah so per
100g so three of these just over is 7g of fat,
5g of saturated fat, 9g of carbs, 8.75g of
sugar, 4.3g of protein so you've got you know
under 3g of sugar in this which is great under
3g of fat in this which is great so bit of fun
delicious strawberry popsicle for
the lovely warm weather that we're
getting here I hope you enjoyed this
nice kidfriendly ice pop video super
easy and quick one for you to try
nice and creamy too not horrible icy
junk nice and before I finish this video some of
you are going to ask why the corn syrup the corn
syrup in this recipe is to create texture
and chew if you take the corn syrup out cuz
you want zero sugar you absolutely can do that
it won't have quite as nice texture but you're
more than welcome to leave that out I like to
leave it in the crap that you can buy for kids
in the stores these days Less Than 3 gr of
sugar in one of these is a Nob brainer for
me she loves eating these she loves that bit
of fun of going into the freezer and grabbing
a Peppa Pig popsicle I hope you try this
one for your kids if you don't have kids
make them for yourself they don't have
to be Peppa Pig of course but hey why
not thanks for much for watching don't forget
to like And subscribe I'll see you next week
[Music]